

RAVI RAJPUT

Web Developer

About Me

Web Developer with 2.5 years experience in helping companies create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Ability to collaborate effectively with senior developers. Enjoy working closely with team members to ensure workloads are effectively redirected to bottlenecks. Eager to tackle more complex problems and continue to find ways to maximize user efficiency.

Professional Experience

Waffle Bytes Pvt Ltd Web Developer | 10 July. 2022 - 22 September. 2023

Key responsibilities:

- · Interact with content team &design team to understand the design
- · Understanding the client requirement & suggest designs
- · Convert figma designs to wordpress websites
- Wordpress theme customization
- Created mutiple websites using elementor pro.
- · Created several ecommerce stores with wordpress using elementor, divi, wpbakery and other page builders.

Craygency by 2nibs Design & Technology Web Developer | 03 Mar. 2022 - 31 Jan. 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Interact with client to understand their requirements & support
- Independently manage projects from development to deployment
- Created UI and UX for websites using figma
- Wordpress theme development
- Created front end of different websites using React JS
- Created several website and ecommerce stores with wordpress using elementor, divi, wpbakery and other page builders.

Freelance Web Developer 1 Oct. 2021 - 15 Feb. 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Understand clients requirements and guide them to choose technology for their projects.
- Created few responsive WordPress websites for startups.
- Created responsive portfolio websites for individuals in React JS.
- Do manual testing of websites.
- Deployment of websites on client servers & aws cloud.
- Design website Ui and UX in figma
- Convert HTML to wordpress theme & plugon customization.
- Created SEO friendly wordpress websites for clients

My Contact



ravirajput8435@gmail.com



+91-7217884801



C-70A, St. no 3, North Chhajjupur, Shahdara, Delhi



ravi-rajput-portfolio.netlify.app

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React JS
- Wordpress
- · AWS Lightsail
- Github
- Figma & Canva
- MySQL

Education

Indira Gandhi National Open University Post Graduate Diploma in Computer App. (PGDCA)

2017 - 2019

 Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University. Bachelors's in Computer Application (BCA)

2014 - 2017

Guru Harkrishan public School 12th CBSE board 10th CBSE board Completed in 2014

Personal Details

• DOB: 27/02/1997

Father's Name: Hakim SinghLanguage Known: Hindi, English.Hobbies: Online Gaming, Reading.

Wordpress Projects

Developed WordPress websites from scratch:

• Yelo Holidays

URL - https://www.yeloholidays.com

• Royale Dreamz

URL - https://royaledreamz.com/

• Pawspace

URL - https://pawspace.in

Craygency

URL - https://craygency.com

• Lap & Dado

URL - https://www.lapanddado.com

• Kathuria & Associates

URL - https://kathuriaandassociates.com

• Thepostyclub

URL - https://www.thepostyclub.com

• Nursing Next Live

URL - https://nursingnextlive.com

• The Sprout Media

URL - https://thesproutmedia.co

• Golden hand

URL - https://goldenhand.in

• Vidit Chess

URL - https://viditchess.com

• Spotsense

URL - https://spotsense.io/

• Amrit Homes

URL - https://www.amrithomes.in

Obasix

URL - https://www.obasix.com

• Straightshotca

URL - https://www.straightshotca.com

• Climbax Group Site

URL - <u>www.climbaxentertainment.com</u>

· Climbax technology

URL - tech.climbaxentertainment.com

• Climbax Digital Marketing

URL - <u>dm.climbaxentertainment.com</u>

• Deewani's Decor

URL - https://deewanisdecor.com

HSN Group

URL - https://www.hsngroup.com

HSN Interiors

URL - https://www.hsninteriors.com

Professional Experience

Climbax Entertainment Pvt Ltd | Front End Developer 01 Oct. 2020 - 30 Sep. 2021

Key responsibilities:

- Have developed scalable front end websites
- Created many responsive websites using React JS, Next JS & Wordpress
- Designed UI and UX for different websites.
- Designed assets for website with graphic designers and digital marketing team members.
- Make documentation for projects.

Climbax Entertainment Pvt Ltd | Web Developer Intern 01 June 2020 - 30 Sep. 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Created WordPress themes from HTML templates.
- Developed website front end using HTML, CSS & JS.

Hitachi Systems Micro Clinic | Technical Support Dec. 2018 - June 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Resolved technical issues over calls.
- Generate tickets of technical issues.
- Provided support to onsite engineers for resolving issue.
- Provided software demonstration to end users.
- Provided support to software products.

Experts Global | Web Developer Intern Nov. 2017 - Dec. 2017

Key responsibilities:

- Created website UI and UX.
- Created different modules for their wordpress website.
- Fix bugs in existing website.

Projects

Portal for gadget review - Gadgets Bee

- Was responsible for creating both frontend and backend
- HTML, CCS, PHP and MySQL was used.
- Repo Link https://github.com/RaviRajput97/Gadgetbee

Web portal for Coworking software - Digicuro

- Component based website
- Was responsible for creating the frontend components
- React JS and Next JS was used

Web portal for Property Listing

- · Property listing website
- Was responsible for creating the frontend components
- React JS and Next JS was used

Web portal for Edutech

- One page static website
- Was responsible for creating the frontend
- HTML & CCS was used
- Link https://hopeful-davinci-702947.netlify.app

Web portal for Fruits & Vegetables Exporter

- HTML, CSS & JS website
- Was responsible for creating the frontend
- · Also responsible for deployment of website
- Link https://www.moonlightfresco.com